Van Chan Ngo

School of Computer Science Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA 15213, USA

Email: channgo@cmu.edu

URL: http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~vanchann/

Current Position

Post-doctoral Researcher, Principles of Programming Languages, School of Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, USA

Areas of Specialization

Programming Languages • Formal Verification • Compilers • Language-based Security

Research Interests

My research activities aim at building reliable and secure computer systems by developing formal frameworks which guarantee that software satisfies formally its specification, especially embedded safety-critical software such as automotive, avionic, and health-care applications. The construction of a formal framework involves the research and knowledge of principles of programming languages, compiler design and development, and formal methods including model checking, theorem proving, and static analysis, to provide formal assurances that the specification is fulfilled.

Education

08/2014	Ph.D in Computer Science, INRIA Rennes-Bretagne Atlantique and Université de Rennes 1, Rennes, France,
	First Class Honors
06/2008	MSc in Computer Science, Université Joseph Fourier, Grenoble, France, under a French Government Scholarship-
	Évariste Galois
07/2005	Engineer in Computer Engineering, Center of Talented Training-PFIEV, Hanoi University of Technology,
	Hanoi Vietnam First Class Honors with Congratulations of the Ministry of Education

Awards & Honors

2017	Schloss Dagstuhl - NSF Support Grant for Junior Researchers, Wadern, Saarland, Germany
2011-2014	Ph.D scholarship, INRIA France
2007-2008	DEA scholarship from the French government, Université de Grenoble, France
2007	Masters scholarship from the Italian government, Politecnico di Milano, Italy
2007	Masters scholarship from SamSung company, ICU-KAIST, South Korea
2000-2005	Scholarships from Hanoi University of Technology for excellent academic results

Employment History

2011-2014

2016-Present	Research Fellow, School of Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, USA
	• Automatic symbolic resource bound (e.g., time and memory) analysis of functional and imperative pro-
	grams for detecting security vulnerability including time side-channel attacks, stack overflow, etc
	• Static analysis for probabilistic programs, e.g., automatic symbolic expected resource bound analysis such
	as execution time and memory usage
2015-2016	Research Engineer, INRIA, Rennes, France

Formal verification of probabilistic SystemC models using Statistical Model Checking
 Probabilistic temporal assertion-based verification of SystemC models

• Probabilistic temporal assertion-based verification of systems; models Research Assistant, INRIA, Rennes, France

• Formal verification of the highly optimizing and industrial synchronous data-flow compiler, Signal, which is used in model-based design of real-time and safety-critical systems

1

• Using translation validation approach to prove the preservation of clock semantics, data dependencies and value-equivalence for source code and the compiled programs using several techniques including model checking, theorem proving, and graph transformation

Software Architect, Tech Propulsion Lab, USA 2010-2011

• Design and development of embedded mobile software on iOS and Android platforms

• Project management in the mobile development department

Research Assistant, IBM Zurich Lab and ZISC, Zurich, Switzerland 2008-2009

· Formally verifying and certifying the design of secure boot processes in IBM AIX mainframes

• Formalizing the boot process and its security properties using Promela and the model checker Spin

2007-2008 Internship, VERIMAG Laboratory, Grenoble, France

> · Automated verification framework for formally proving the IND-CPA security property of asymmetric encryption schemes

> • Representing the encryption schemes as frames in cryptographic π -calculus, and formalizing the IND-CPA property as a equivalent relation between two frames

Senior Software Engineer, IBM, Hanoi, Vietnam 2006-2007

• Working on text search engine of the IBM data base management DB2

Software Engineer, FPT Software, Hanoi, Vietnam 2005-2006 · Working on embedded systems for navigation

Technical Strengths

Programming Languages

• Strong knowledge: C/C++, OCaml • Familiarity: Assembly, Java, Python

Toolchains • Strong knowledge: GCC, LLVM Compiler Infrastructure

Formal Methods & Model· Strong knowledge: Synchronous Programming, Logics and Temporal Logics, Model Checking, Theorem

Proving, Static Analysis • Familiarity: SystemC, Verilog

ing Languages

Formal Method • Strong knowledge: SPIN, SMV, UPAAL, PRISM, SMC Plasma Lab, Yices, Z3, Coq, Frama-C

Embedded Soft- • Familiarity: AVR, Arduino, RTLinux, FreeRTOS

ware Develop-

ment

Languages

• English: Advance • French: Advance • Vietnamese: Native

Publications

According to the core conference ranking, TOP* denotes a flagship conference or premium journal (e.g. rank A*) or a premium journal, while **TOP** denotes a good conference or a leading journal (e.g. rank A, B).

Journal & Conference

V.C. Ngo, Q. Carbonneaux, and J. Hoffmann. Bounded Expectations: Resource Analysis for Probabilistic Pro-2018 grams. In Proceedings of 2018 ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI'18). ACM, Philadelphia, PA, USA. Acceptance rate: 55/275 = 20.0% TOP*

V.C. Ngo, M. Dehesa-Azuara, M. Fredrikson, J. Hoffmann. Verifying and Synthesizing Constant-Resource Im-2017 plementations with Types. In Proceedings of 38th IEEE Symposium on Security & Privacy (SP Oakland'17). IEEE, San Jose, CA, USA. Acceptance rate: 60/463 = 12.9% TOP*

V.C. Ngo and A. Legay. Formal Verification of Probabilistic SystemC Models with Statistical Model Checking. 2017 In Journal of Software: Evolution and Process. Wiley. TOP

V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and V. Joloboff. PSCV: A Runtime Verification Tool for Probabilistic SystemC Models. In 2016 Proceedings of 28th International Conference on Computer Aided Verification (CAV'16). Springer, Toronto, Ontario, Canada. Acceptance rate: 58/195 = 29.7% TOP* 2016

V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and J. Quilbeuf. Statistical Model Checking for SystemC Models. In Proceedings of 17th High Assurance Systems Engineering Symposium (HASE'16). IEEE, Orlando, Florida, USA. Acceptance rate: 32/78 = 41% **TOP**

V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, L. Besnard, and P. Le Guernic. Modular Translation Validation of a Full-sized 2015

- Synchronous Compiler using Off-the-shelf Verification Tools. In Proceedings of International Workshop on Software and Compilers for Embedded Systems (SCOPES'15). ACM, St. Goar, Germany. Acceptance rate: 8/18 = 44.4% TOP
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, and T. Gautier. *Translation Validation for Synchronous Data-flow Specification in the SIGNAL Compiler*. In Proceedings of 35th IFIP International Conference on Formal Techniques for Distributed Objects, Components and Systems (FORTE'15). IFIP, Grenoble, France. Acceptance rate: 15/53 = 28.3% TOP
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, and P. Le Guernic. *Translation Validation for Clock Transformations in a Synchronous Compiler*. In Proceedings of 18th International Conference on Fundamental Approaches to Software Engineering (FASE'15). Springer, London, UK. Acceptance rate: 23/80 = 28.7% TOP
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, and T. Gautier. *Precise Deadlock Detection for Polychronous Data-flow Specifications*. In Proceedings of the Electronic System Level Synthesis Conference (ESLsyn-DAC'14). IEEE, San Francisco, CA, USA
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. *Formal Verification of Synchronous Data-flow Program Transformations Toward Certified Compilers*. In Journal of Frontiers of Computer Science. Special Issue on Synchronous Programming, Springer
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. Formal Verification of Automatically Generated C-code from Polychronous Data-flow Equations. Accepted at International High-Level Design, Validation and Test Workshop (HLDVT'12). IEEE, California, USA
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. Formal Verification of Compiler Transformations on Polychronous Equations. In Proceedings of 9th International Conference on Integrated Formal Methods (IFM'12). Springer, Pisa, Italy. Acceptance rate: 22/59 = 37% TOP
- C. Ene, Y. Lakhnech, and V.C. Ngo (Authors by alphabetical order). Formal Indistinguishability Extended to the Random Oracle Model. In Proceedings of 14th European Symposium on Research in Computer Security (ESORICS'09). Springer, Saint-Malo, France. Acceptance rate: 42/220 = 19.1% TOP
- 2009 C. Ene, Y. Lakhnech, and V.C. Ngo (Authors by alphabetical order). Formal Indistinguishability Extended to the ROM. In Proceedings of Workshop on Formal and Computational Cryptography (FCC'09), New York, NY, USA

Thesis

- V.C. Ngo. Formal Verification of a Synchronous Data-flow Compiler: from Signal to C. In Ph.D Thesis in Computer Science, INRIA France, University of Rennes 1, France
- 2008 V.C. Ngo. Automated Verification of Asymmetric Encryption. In MSc Thesis in Computer Science and Applied Mathematics, VERIMAG, University of Grenoble, France
- V.C. Ngo. *Theory and Implementation of Distributed Firewall on Linux Environment* (in Vietnamese). In Engineer Thesis in Computer Engineerings, Center for Talent Training, Hanoi University of Technology, Hanoi, Vietnam

Technical Report

- v.C. Ngo, Q. Carbonneaux, and J. Hoffmann. *Bounded Expectations: Resource Analysis for Probabilistic Programs*. In CMU, Technical Report
- V.C. Ngo, M. Fredrikson, and J. Hoffmann. Quantifying and Preventing Side Channels with Sub-structural Type Systems. In CMU, Technical Report
- V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and J. Quilbeuf. Dependability Analysis of Embedded Control Systems Using SystemC and Statistical Model Checking. In HAL-INRIA, Technical Report RR-8762
- V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and J. Quilbeuf. Dynamic Verification of SystemC Specification with Statistical Model Checking. In HAL-INRIA, Technical Report RR-8644
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, and P. Le Guernic. *Evaluating SDVG Translation Validation: from Signal to C*. In HAL-INRIA, Technical Report RR-8508
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, and P. Le Guernic. Formal Verification of Transformations on Abstract Clocks in Synchronous Compilers. In HAL-INRIA, Technical Report RR-8064
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. Formal Verification of Synchronous Data-flow Compilers. In HAL-INRIA, Technical Report RR-7921

Software

Absynth Automatic Bound Synthesizer (Absynth) is a tool that automatically and statically computes upper bounds on the expected resource usage for imperative probabilistic programs

RAML Resource Aware ML is a tool that automatically and statically computes bounds on resource usage (lower, constant, and upper bounds) for functional programs. It also can check the constant resource-use programs used in preventing timing side-channel attacks **PSCV** A runtime verification tool for probabilistic SystemC models. It consists of two components: the plug-in for Plasma Lab in Java and tool for generating C++ monitor and aspect advices in C++ Plasma Lab Plasma Lab is a compact, efficient and flexible platform for statistical model checking of stochastic models Polychrony The Polychrony tool-set developed in C++ and Java, based on Signal, provides a formal framework to design, develop and validate critical systems, from abstract specification until deployment on distributed systems SigCert The tool developed in OCaml checks the correctness of the compilation of Signal compiler w.r.t clock semantics, data dependence, and value-equivalence (not fully implemented) PDS Simulation Relation Checking with SIGALI: implementation of the theory works in IFM 2012 article as SigCV the libraries in SIGALI tool-set Mobile Appli-Mobile applications: RATP, Turnstone, Saigon Places, A86, PhotoEnc,... cations **Talks** Bounded Expectations: Resource Analysis for Probabilistic Programs - Tool Demonstration. Talk at Dagtuhl 2017 Seminar 17291, Wadern, Germany, July 2017 Verifying and Synthesizing Constant-Resource Implementations with Types. Talk at S&P Oakland 2017, San 2017 Jose, CA, USA, May 2017 PSCV: A Runtime Verification Tool for Probabilistic SystemC Models. Talk at CAV 2016, Toronto, Ontario, 2016 Canada, July 2016 Statistical Model Checking for SystemC Models. Talk at HASE 2016, Orlando, FL, USA, January 2016 2016 Translation Validation for Synchronous Data-flow Specification in the SIGNAL Compiler. Talk at FORTE-2015 DisCoTec 2015, Grenoble, France, June 2015 Translation Validation for Clock Transformations in a Synchronous Compiler. Talk at FASE-ETAPS 2015, Lon-2015 don, UK, April 2015 2015 Dependability Analysis of Embedded Control Systems using SystemC and Statistical Model Checking. Talk at INRIA Rennes, France, March 2015 Precise Deadlock Detection for Polychronous Data-flow Specifications. Talk at ESLsyn-DAC 2014, San Fran-2014 cisco, CA, USA, June 2014 Seminar: Compilation and Execution of Streaming Programs. St Germain au Mont d'Or, France, April 2014 2014 Formal Verification of Transformations on Clocks in Synchronous Data-flow Compilers. Talk at 19th Open 2012 International Workshop on Synchronous Programming 2012, Le Croisic, France, November 2012 Formal Verification of Transformations on Clocks in Synchronous Data-flow Compilers. Talk at Beihang Uni-2012 versity (BUAA), Beijing, China, October 2012 Formal Verification of Compiler Transformations on Polychronous Equations. Talk at IFM 2012, Pisa, Italy, 2012 Formal Indistinguishability Extended to the Random Oracle Model. Talk at ESORICS 2009, Le Croisic, France, 2009 September 2009 **Teaching** Mechanizing Soundness Proofs of the Automatic Amortized Resource Analysis, Student project in Computer 2016 Science, Carnegie Mellon University Introduction to Model Checking, Teaching assistant, Master in Computer Science, University of Rennes 1 2013 Automaton-based Modeling and Formal Verification, Teaching assistant, Master in Computer Science, Uni-2012 versity of Rennes 1 High School Student Teaching in Mathematics and Physics, Tutor, Hanoi University of Technology 2000-2003 **Professional Service** IEEE Embedded Systems Letters (CEDA), 2018 2018 PC Member: Developments in Implicit Computational Complexity (DICE'18), Thessaloniki, Greece, April 2018 2018 ACM Transactions on Programming Languages and Systems (TOPLAS), 2018 2018

The 29th International Conference on Computer Aided Verification (CAV'17), Heidelberg, Germany, July 2017

2017

The ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI'17), Barcelona, Spain, June 2017

The 26th International Conference on Compiler Construction (CC'17), Austin, Texas, US, February 2017
The 16th International Conference on Formal Methods in Computer-Aided Design (FMCAD'16), Mountain View. CA. US. October 2016

The 27th International Conference on Concurrency Theory (CONCUR'16), Quebec City, Canada, August 2016
The 13th ACM-IEEE International Conference on Formal Methods and Models for System Design (MEMOCODE'15),
Austin, US, September 2015

The 8th International Conference on Language and Automata Theory and Applications (LATA'14), Madrid, Spain, March 2014

Research Projects

This is a DARPA-funded project and will be 48 months in duration. The project involves many Research & Development teams in industry and university research groups, e.g., GrammaTech, Draper, University of Utah, University of Colorado Boulder, Iowa State University, and Carnegie Mellon University. STAC program aims to develop new program analysis techniques and associated tools for identifying vulnerabilities related to the space and time resource usage behavior of algorithms, specifically, vulnerabilities to algorithmic complexity and side-channel attacks. It seeks to enable developers to identify vulnerabilities related to resource usage in software at language levels. The applications will be the information systems that U.S. government, military, and economy depend

The project focuses on the development of a new methodology to support evolving, adaptive and iterative System of Systems (SoS) life-cycle models based on a formal semantics for SoS inter-operations and supported by novel tools for analysis, simulation, and optimization. DANSE includes industrial representatives with focus on aerospace, land, and automotive systems, as well as a leading tools and framework provider in the system space, and top European research institutes in system engineering. These partners have deep interest in the outcome of the research and are eager to deploy the developments as soon as they become available

The DALI project has undertaken a challenging agenda aimed at extending the people autonomous life beyond the home. The environment where the system operates is partially known (due to its large variability) and changing. Our assisted living device system must therefore acquire dynamic information about the user's immediate environment in order to guide its decision-making. The construction of a system of such complexity represents a major scientific and technological effort bringing together expertise across different disciplines

The project proposed here aims at substantially improving the safety and reliability of embedded software that is being developed in the context of a Model-based design approach. This is achieved by formally proving the correctness of essential transformations that a model undergoes during its compilation to executable code. The definition of the semantics and the correctness proof of the compiler will be carried out by means of theorem proving. The compiler is executable and will be evaluated on realistic examples. The project is targeted at the compilation of a synchronous language to an imperative programming language. Synchronous languages have turned out to be an expressive formalism for embedded algorithms, and their precise semantics make them particularly suitable for our purpose

Our day-to-day lives increasingly depend upon information and our ability to manipulate it securely. That is, in a way that prevents malicious elements to subvert the available information for their own benefits. This requires solutions based on cryptographic systems (primitives and protocols). However, no matter how carefully crafted cryptographic systems are, experience has shown that effective attacks can remain hidden for years. This may be caused by poor design or often unclear and poorly defined security properties and assumptions. The goal of this project is to achieve a major step towards building automated tools for the verification of cryptographic systems. In order, to reconcile generality, imposed by the high diversity of cryptographic systems, and automation, we shall build our tools upon Coq

Electronic voting promises the possibility of a convenient, efficient and secure facility for recording and tallying votes. However, the convenience of electronic elections comes with a risk of large-scale fraud and their security has seriously been questioned. In this project we propose to use formal methods to analyze electronic voting protocols

2014

DALI

VERISYNC

SCALP

AVOTE